<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jquery Mobile on Alex Bachuk</title>
    <link>https://alexbachuk.com/tags/jquery-mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jquery Mobile on Alex Bachuk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 01:34:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexbachuk.com/tags/jquery-mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress and Phonegap (part3)</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/05/28/wordpress-and-phonegap-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 01:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/05/28/wordpress-and-phonegap-part3/</guid>
      <description>In part 1 and 2 we learned how to prepare everything for our mobile app: get data from WordPress in JSON format and setup jQuery mobile and Phonegap boilerplate. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get the mobile app actually do something, in this case I will build app fro my blog and portfolio to demonstrate how to work with different post types.
I will build iOS app, but the same technique applies to Android, Windows phone, Blackberry, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress and Phonegap (part2)</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/05/14/wordpress-and-phonegap-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 04:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/05/14/wordpress-and-phonegap-part2/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, we learned how to get WordPress to work as backend platform for our future mobile app. Now we have nicely formatted JSON feed coming from WordPress and we can use it anywhere with ajax request. This part will explain how to get phonegap set up and prepare some boilerplate for our app using jQuery Mobile, CSS and HTML.
Phonegap has really well explained guides on setting up phonegap locally for iOS, Android or any other target platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery Mobile Active Page URL</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/02/13/jquery-mobile-active-page-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 19:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/02/13/jquery-mobile-active-page-url/</guid>
      <description>jQuery mobile contains several pages in DOM at once to make page transition smooth and fast, and also pre-caching static pages. If you need to get current URL, and decided to use
window.location.href   it will return previous page URL, because active page is inserted into the DOM via AJAX. To get current page URL use
$.mobile.activePage[0].baseURI
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>