<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fluent on Alex Bachuk</title>
    <link>/tags/fluent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fluent on Alex Bachuk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 22:20:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/fluent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluent 2014 Conference review</title>
      <link>/2014/03/15/fluent-2014-conference-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 22:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/03/15/fluent-2014-conference-review/</guid>
      <description>The Fluent conference was great. San Francisco, sunny weather, good food, awesome speakers, a lot of new content. A lot of sessions was about performance and angular.js. I was expecting more discussions around Node.js, but I guess this is front end conference.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_711&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;700&amp;rdquo;]Inventor of JavaScript Brandon Eich, keynote. [/caption]
Angular.js clearly has won JavaScript MVC battle. Last year (different conference though) I saw a lot more sessions on Backbone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluent 2014 conference day 1</title>
      <link>/2014/03/13/fluent-2014-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 06:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/03/13/fluent-2014-day1/</guid>
      <description>Fluent is annual conference in San Francisco mostly about JavaScript. It&amp;rsquo;s my first time to this conference and San Francisco.
The conference started with day of workshops, I attended workshops on automating all things front-end, web RTC and Angular.js fundamentals. To be honest, I was expecting more hands-on practice, but I still was able to learn something new.
Front end workflow automation is all about grunt tasks and plugins. I was familiar with some of the tools mentioned here, like livereload, which is huge time saver while working locally, it compiles sass, less, haml, and other on the fly and updates web page automatically without reloading, definitely a must have for any developer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>