<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Node.Js on Alex Bachuk</title>
    <link>/tags/node.js/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Node.Js on Alex Bachuk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 15:08:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/node.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Weekend List #01</title>
      <link>/javascript-weekend-list-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 15:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/javascript-weekend-list-01/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying something new. Every week I’ll try to come up with the list of most interesting articles, books, news, tutorials and videos about web development. I’ll be using this list to keep myself up-to-date on everything that’s going on in the JavaScript, Node and front-end development community. This list may not have the most recent articles, but rather relevant content to stay sharp as a full stack developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading files with React.js and Node.js</title>
      <link>/2016/12/17/uploading-files-with-react-js-and-node-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 14:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/17/uploading-files-with-react-js-and-node-js/</guid>
      <description>Uploading files is one of the most common tasks performed by web developers. It’s a pretty simple operation when using PHP or other server side frameworks. However, it is not so straightforward when using Node.js, unless you understand how to user Buffer API for reading streams of binary files (i.e. uploading file content as binary code). Luckily for us, the Node.js community came up with a few solutions.
Project set up We are using React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive express.js and angular.js application</title>
      <link>/2015/11/24/adaptive-express-js-and-angular-js-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 03:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/11/24/adaptive-express-js-and-angular-js-application/</guid>
      <description>Mobile web is growing really fast and for some businesses it is a significant (if not majority) amount of traffic. The experience on mobile could be slightly different than desktop or it could be completely different depending on the project or the app. For example, marketing or news website might have similar experience, since its only goal is to deliver the content in accessible way. But, for other websites, like e-commerce mobile experience might be have totally different meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>