<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Alex Bachuk</title>
    <link>https://alexbachuk.com/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Alex Bachuk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 15:08:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexbachuk.com/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Weekend List #01</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/javascript-weekend-list-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 15:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/javascript-weekend-list-01/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying something new. Every week I’ll try to come up with the list of most interesting articles, books, news, tutorials and videos about web development. I’ll be using this list to keep myself up-to-date on everything that’s going on in the JavaScript, Node and front-end development community. This list may not have the most recent articles, but rather relevant content to stay sharp as a full stack developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send emails with Ember.js &#43; Amazon SES &#43; Firebase</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/send-emails-with-ember-js-amazon-ses-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 15:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/send-emails-with-ember-js-amazon-ses-firebase/</guid>
      <description>There is a need to build client side only (front end) applications. Tools like Ember CLI, Create react app, Angular 2 CLI make it very easy to bootstrap a JavaScript app in just a few minutes and start building features.
The challenge arises when you need to add a piece of server side logic, like sending emails, uploading files, authentication, or storing some data to the database. In most cases, it doesn’t make sense to add a full blown server, which requires to be maintained and setup .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading files with React.js and Node.js</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/12/17/uploading-files-with-react-js-and-node-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 14:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/12/17/uploading-files-with-react-js-and-node-js/</guid>
      <description>Uploading files is one of the most common tasks performed by web developers. It’s a pretty simple operation when using PHP or other server side frameworks. However, it is not so straightforward when using Node.js, unless you understand how to user Buffer API for reading streams of binary files (i.e. uploading file content as binary code). Luckily for us, the Node.js community came up with a few solutions.
Project set up We are using React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education for web developers</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/03/25/education-for-web-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 19:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/03/25/education-for-web-developers/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a web developer for over 8 years, and got hooked on web development the very first time I wrote HTML. The process of creating something people can use out of nothing is very powerful. Before I began my career in web development, I was doing construction and then later help-desk work. To me, programming is similar to construction. You have a problem, and you need to figure out the solution, using your skills and the tools available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why web developers need side projects</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/03/05/why-web-developers-need-side-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 18:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/03/05/why-web-developers-need-side-projects/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, when I was working at a startup (Ruby on Rails app) as a front end developer, from time to time I had to go in and make back end changes. It was terrifying because I didn’t know what I was doing. I decided to learn Rails and bought books and took online courses. However, it wasn’t as easy as I thought, because I only had front end background and some WordPress experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React.js route state name</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/01/10/react-js-route-state-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/01/10/react-js-route-state-name/</guid>
      <description>React.js router is at version 2.0 as of now. It’s changing fast. So this may not work few months from now. I had the case where I wanted to create REST URLs but still re-use components where possible. That’s one of the selling points of React as a library. In my case I wanted to re-use form in the “new” and “update” pages. Here is how I got it working:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning React.js and Redux</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/01/03/learning-react-js-and-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 20:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2016/01/03/learning-react-js-and-redux/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR I had a hard time learning React.js, because it requires complex boilerplate setup, tooling and special application architecture such as Flux or Redux. After watching many intro videos or tutorials I wasn’t making progress until I decided to develop simple open source project with React+Redux using open source boilerplate. As I try to make every feature - I’m learning how to do it with React+Redux and sometimes asking questions on Stackoverflow or Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive express.js and angular.js application</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/11/24/adaptive-express-js-and-angular-js-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 03:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/11/24/adaptive-express-js-and-angular-js-application/</guid>
      <description>Mobile web is growing really fast and for some businesses it is a significant (if not majority) amount of traffic. The experience on mobile could be slightly different than desktop or it could be completely different depending on the project or the app. For example, marketing or news website might have similar experience, since its only goal is to deliver the content in accessible way. But, for other websites, like e-commerce mobile experience might be have totally different meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload files with meteor.js, aws and froala wysiwyg package</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/10/06/upload-files-with-meteor-js-aws-and-froala-wysiwyg-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/10/06/upload-files-with-meteor-js-aws-and-froala-wysiwyg-package/</guid>
      <description>It’s not very easy to upload files directly to Meteor, although there is a way to “emulate” file system and upload files directly to your server, why not use Amazon S3, which very cheap and fast to host static files. I find that having the separation gives some peace of mind, you can deploy your app, change servers, even delete the app or re-build it from the ground up, without affecting your or users&amp;rsquo; static files such as images, videos, documents, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Application development book review and free giveaway</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/06/30/wordpress-application-development-book-review-and-free-giveaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 11:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/06/30/wordpress-application-development-book-review-and-free-giveaway/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Packtpub was kind enough to give me 2 digital copies to give away to my readers. Please leave a comment below, add a sentence or two what app you&amp;rsquo;re working on or why you&amp;rsquo;d like to win this book. I&amp;rsquo;ll pick 2 winners on July 12th.
WordPress has come along way from being just a blogging platform to becoming a full-featured CMS site. It is now even being used as a platform for web and mobile applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web performance and how to optimize a website for speed</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/06/08/web-performance-and-how-to-optimize-a-website-for-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 02:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/06/08/web-performance-and-how-to-optimize-a-website-for-speed/</guid>
      <description>The average website load time is 2.45 seconds, according to Google Analytics blog, posted in 2012. http://analytics.blogspot.com/2012/04/global-site-speed-overview-how-fast-are.html. Users are increasingly becoming more impatient, they expect a page to load fast. Especially mobile users, who are mostly on the go and need to access the information fast. Companies like amazon and google invest a lot of effort and have dedicated teams who work on improving not only their websites but helping others to do the same with their websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a better web developer</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/04/28/become-a-better-web-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 14:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2015/04/28/become-a-better-web-developer/</guid>
      <description>Recently I attended Fluent conference and saw very interesting presentation by Kathy Sierra (SeriousPony). It was about making badass developers. Since I&amp;rsquo;m trying to be a better web developer myself and constantly improve, I did a little more digging and found some useful information and tips.
What skill do you need to have to be web developer? Some consider themselves as web developers when they can do HTML and some CSS, some - when they know JavaScript and some would like to add PHP to the list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My experience with backbone.js and require.js</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/11/29/my-experience-with-backbone-js-and-require-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 23:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/11/29/my-experience-with-backbone-js-and-require-js/</guid>
      <description>Backbone.js is&amp;hellip; as some say - just another javascript plugin. And technically it is just 6KB javascript plugin that you can add to pretty much any website or web application, it&amp;rsquo;s MV* library, not a framework. There are not strict rules, developer has freedom to choose their own style of writing an app, for better or worse :)
Some background: I&amp;rsquo;ve built few web applications with Backbone.js, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any experience with any other MV* javascript library or framework, so it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to compare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay up to date with front-end development </title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/07/17/stay-up-to-date-with-front-end-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 01:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/07/17/stay-up-to-date-with-front-end-development/</guid>
      <description>My day job is front end web developer. That means I write JavaScript, HTML and CSS every single day (in that order). Front end development is not about static html pages anymore and JavaScript is not just for animations. It&amp;rsquo;s much more than that. You can build any web application with these open source technologies, including on the server side (Node.js).
In this space web browsers are the ones who dictate how we, as developers, can utilize latest and greatest tricks, CSS3 animations and layout syntax (flexbox, columns), HTML5 APIs(localstorage, geolocation), JavaScript methods(map, pluck).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript templates</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/06/22/javascript-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 16:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/06/22/javascript-templates/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript is the most used programming language now, it&amp;rsquo;s very powerful and can do more than home page slideshow or animations. AJAX is a big part of JavaScript and one of the reasons this language is so popular. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to get any content from the server and send any content back to server, two way communication. Libraries and frameworks like Backbone.js make this process very elegant and organized. Few years ago it was a standard proces to append html in AJAX callback to the DOM, and it works, and if it&amp;rsquo;s done right (append all the content at once instead of at each iteration of a loop), it&amp;rsquo;s even ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backbone.js explained</title>
      <link>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/04/29/backbone-js-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 20:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexbachuk.com/2013/04/29/backbone-js-explained/</guid>
      <description>Backbone.js is one of many javascript MVC frameworks, others are Angular.js, Phantom.js, Ember.js. Why backbone? It&amp;rsquo;s very small, only 6K minified, not opinionated, meaning it doesn&amp;rsquo;t dictate how you should organize your code. A lot of big companies (like Pandora, USA Today, New York Times, Rdio) use backbone.js to power their web applications.
What can Backbone.js do for you? If you write any javascript code at all - you will appreciate the power backbone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>